hoax-slayer.com 2014-02-20

# Privacy Policy

I will never sell or give away your email address, or any other personal information, for any reason whatsoever. 

©iStockphoto.com/Marco Volpi

The Hoax-Slayer Newsletter email notification service uses a double opt-in subscription system that ensures that you really did want to subscribe. The email address that you provide when subscribing is used solely for delivering the monthly notification email and administrative emails such as subscription and unsubscription notices. The subscription process is outlined below: 

  1. Access the simple online subscription form available on the [Subscription Options](http://www.hoax-slayer.com/subscription-options.shtml) page.
  2. Enter your email address, and click the button. All being well, you will receive a confirmation email.
  3. Finalize the subscription by using the link provided in the confirmation email. When you follow this link, by clicking it or copying and pasting it into your browser address bar, your email address will be immediately added to the list of subscribers and you will receive a "Welcome" email confirming your subscription.

If you decide that you no longer wish to receive Hoax-Slayer Newsletter notification emails, unsubscribing is a simple process. There are two ways to unsubscribe:

  1. Click the "Change address / Leave mailing list" link at the bottom of every notification email and enter your email address into the form provided. Once you have submitted your email address via the unsubscribe form, your address will be immediately removed from the list of subscribers.
  2. Visit the alternative [Unsubscribe Page](http://www.hoax-slayer.com/unsub.shtml) and follow the instructions.

Once the unsubscription process is completed, your email address will no longer be listed in the subscriber database. You should receive a final email confirming your unsubscription. If a newsletter notifications mail-out is in progress at the time your unsubscribe, you may also receive one final notification email. However, you will not receive subsequent newsletter notifications or any other emails from me unless I am replying to a personal email you have sent. To deliver notification emails to subscribers, I use the service provided by [YourMailingListProvider.com](http://www.yourmailinglistprovider.com/).

Hoax-Slayer is totally anti-spam. I will never send unsolicited advertising email. In fact, I have a personal policy of NEVER buying a product or service as a result of spam email, regardless of its intrinsic worth.

In order to use some services provided on the Hoax-Slayer site it might be necessary to provide information such as your name and email address. These services include the newsletter subscription form, and Hoax-Slayer Social. None of the information you provide will be used for any purpose other than that for which it was originally intended. 

Hoax-Slayer uses [Google Analytics](http://www.google.com/analytics/ "Google Analytics") to record and process statistical information such as the number of visitors to the website, what pages are the most popular and system information such as the operating system and browser used by visitors. Any information collected is solely for statistical purposes and is not used to identify individuals in any way. In order to provide meaningful reports about visits to the site, Google Analytics may send cookies to your computer. Browser privacy settings allow you to block or restrict cookies as desired. Cookies may also be controlled by the use of privacy and security software provided by a number of vendors.

The Hoax-Slayer website uses advertising provided by [Google AdSense](https://www.google.com/adsense/support/bin/topic.py?topic=8421 "Google AdSense") to generate revenue. While I would never knowingly include advertisements that promote fraudulent products or companies, I take no responsibility for the overall conduct or reliability of companies or services that advertise on the site. In the course of ads being served on this website, third party advertisements may place or read cookies on your browser or use web beacons to collect information. You can control the use of cookies via the privacy settings of your web browser. Browser privacy settings allow you to block or restrict cookies as desired. Cookies and web beacons may also be controlled by the use of privacy and security software provided by a number of vendors.

The [DoubleClick DART cookie](http://www.doubleclick.com/privacy/faq.aspx "DoubleClick DART cookie") may be used by Google in the Google ads served on this website. When users visit Hoax-Slayer and either view or click on an ad, a cookie may be dropped on the user's browser. 

  * Google, as a third party vendor, uses cookies to serve ads on this site.
  * Google's use of the DART cookie enables it to serve ads based on a user's visit to this site and other sites on the Internet.
  * Users may opt out of the use of the DART cookie by visiting the [Google ad and content network privacy policy](http://www.google.com/privacy_ads.html "Google ad and content network privacy policy").

Listed below are the third party companies that may serve ads on this website via Google AdSense . These companies may use information (not including your name, address, email address, or telephone number) about your visits to this and other websites in order to provide advertisements about goods and services of interest to you. If you would like more information about this practice and to know your choices about not having this information used by these companies and/or opting out of any cookies used by these companies, please visit the company websites via the links provided in the following list: 

  * DoubleClick([www.doubleclick.com](http://www.doubleclick.com/))
  * Mediaplex ([www.mediaplex.com](http://www.mediaplex.com/))
  * Eyeblaster ([www.eyeblaster.com](http://www.eyeblaster.com/))
  * EyeWonder ([www.eyewonder.com](http://www.eyewonder.com/))
  * Interpolls ([www.interpolls.com](http://www.interpolls.com/))
  * Pointroll ([www.pointroll.com](http://www.pointroll.com/))
  * Unicast ([www.unicast.com](http://www.unicast.com/))
  * Dynamic Logic/Safecount ([www.safecount.net](http://www.safecount.net/privacy.htm))
  * Factor TG ([www.factortg.com](http://www.factortg.com/))
  * IAG ([www.iagr.com](http://www.iagr.net/))
  * InsightExpress ([www.insightexpress.com](http://www.insightexpress.com/))

I also participate in a limited number of affiliate marketing programs. Clicking on a link or banner for an affiliate product may cause a cookie to be sent to your browser. The site may include reviews or recommendations for carefully chosen affiliate products. For more details, view the [Hoax-Slayer Affiliate Marketing Policy](http://www.hoax-slayer.com/affiliate-marketing-policy.html).

Many pages on the Hoax-Slayer website include an in-page commenting system provided by [Disqus](http://disqus.com/home/ "Disqus"). This system allows readers to offer comments or feedback about information published on the website. In order to use the commenting system, users are required to provide a name or nickname and an email address. Neither Disqus nor I will share this information with third parties or use it for any purpose other than that which it was originally intended. You can read the Disqus privacy policy [here](http://disqus.com/docs/terms/ "Disqus: Terms and Privacy"). Comments that include unsolicited advertising material (spam), foul language, racist, sexist, pornographic, or defamatory remarks, potential copyright or privacy infringements or links to websites that may pose security risks to site visitors or contain pornography or other material that site visitors may find disturbing will be rejected or deleted without notice. In order to stop spam and other unsuitable material from appearing on the website, I reserve the right to moderate, reject or delete any comments posted on the site. All comments published on the site reflect the views and opinions of their authors. I do not necessarily condone or agree with these views or opinions. In order to provide the commenting system, Disqus may send cookies to your computer. Browser privacy settings allow you to block or restrict cookies as desired. Cookies may also be controlled by the use of privacy and security software provided by a number of vendors.

As an Internet user, online privacy is an important issue for me, in respect to both my privacy and yours. If you have any concerns, comments, or questions regarding this Privacy Policy, please [contact me](mailto:catch@hoax-slayer.com) and I'll do my best to help.
